MEHMET YURTAR

FRONTEND DEVELOPER

Mobile: +905078268205 http://mehmetyurtar.me/ https://www.linkedin.com/in/yurtarmehmet/

SUMMARY

I am a product-focused frontend developer building rich web applications with user experience in mind.
I have a huge passion for sharing what I know with people, so I also occasionaly involve frontend development bootcamps as an instructor.

SKILLS

- JavaScript
- TypeScript
- HTML
- CSS
- Sass
- React
- Redux
- Angular
- jQuery
- GraphQL
- Node.js
- Single Page Applications
- Progressive Web

Applications

- Next.js
- Server Side Rendering

TRAINER EXPERIENCE

- Kodluyoruz Frontend Bootcamp - April 2020
- Kodluyoruz React Bootcamp
 - October 2019

EDUCATION

 Yıldız Technical University Bachelor's degree in Mathematics

2011 - Present

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Frontend Developer

Cimri.com | September 2019 - Present

Cimri.com is a price comparison website.

We're a team of 6 frontend developers in cimri.com. In this 1 year period, I had the chance to build and maintain large-scale projects, mainly based on React.

- We built a frontend architecture for JWT based authentication.
- I built a comparison module, so users can compare multiple products in one ux-friendly screen.
- I built brochures page.
- We published a brand new backoffice webapp for internal use in cimri.
- I also lead the team especially for technical issues.

Frontend Developer

Migros Ticaret | February 2019 - September 2019
Migros Ticaret A.Ş. is one of the biggest chains of
supermarkets in Turkey. I was responsible for maintaining all
the e-commerce web applications containing
sanalmarket.com and tazedirekt.com. We built the brand
new user interface for tazedirekt.com with Angular and Rx. It
is also a progressive web app. I had to chance to learn
Angular deeply as a React developer, so my experience here
was so enlightening.

Frontend Developer

Segmentify | July 2016 - February 2019, Istanbul - San Francisco

Segmentify is an ecommerce personalisation platform that helps online retailers to deliver unique shopping experience to their visitors. Some of the thins I did there:

- Developing and maintaining the new React and Redux based user Panel.
- Developing and maintaining the Chrome Extension of the product. Using React on the frontend.
- Implementing the product features in client websites. Mostly using JavaScript, jQuery, CSS and HTML
- Maintaining the extensions of the product on ecommerce platforms (Shopify, Prestashop)
- I had the chance to work in San Francisco office for 6 months and experienced fully remote work.

Frontend Developer

Nuevo Softwarehouse | April 2015 - March 2016 Developing user interfaces for projects based on ASP.NET and Sharepoint. Using JavaScript, Angular, Jquery. CSS and HTMI